MIKKEL CHAMBERS

Mikkel.P.Chambers@gmail.com • Mobile + 1 507 696 7190 • https://therealmpchambers.github.io/MPC_Profile1/

Placeholder

Professional individual skilled at strategic and tactical execution. Enjoys being part of a team as well as working individually. Able to manage high stake conflict resolution and problem solving with external and internal stakeholders with a win-win mindset. Knowledgeable in front and back end web application design with a joy for designing responsive webpages, a curiosity for JavaScript, and enthusiasm for expanding expertise.

Characteristics include:

- Analytical
- Excel Wizard
- Creative
- Achiever
- Solution Architect Committed
- Feedback Oriented
- Collaborative
- Adaptable
- Diligent
- Detailed
- Ethical

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

3WIRE – A MARMON/BERKSHIRE HATHAWAY COMPANY | Osseo, MN | 2015 – 2018

3Wire is a foodservice and beverage company.

Sales and Operations Buyer

Supported the strategic direction outlined by Senior Leadership Team by establishing processes and procedures that reduced workload by 15%, improved delivery performance by an average of 4.7 days, and increased stock metrics by 23% while reducing total cost of inventory. Managed internal and external stakeholder relationships involving ontime delivery, tech services, and OEM/OCM manufacturing schedules. Designed and implemented excel macros and dashboards that automated redundant supply chain tasks.

TARGET CORPORATE | Minneapolis, MN | 2014-2015

Target Corporation is an American retailing company, founded in 1902.

Merchandise Specialist

Supported monthly vendor forecast cycle and ensured contract terms were met. Implemented agreements between Buyers and Vendors. Organized various marketing programs between miscellaneous business partners and ensured data accuracy for each program. Assisted and implemented inventory tactics to support assortment and merchandise plans while achieving service level and inventory turn targets which ensured that stores stayed in stock to support their ability to sell merchandise.

KLINE AUTO WORLD | Maplewood, MN | 2014-2014

Kline Auto World is a locally family-owned dealership that specializes in selling Nissan, Volvo, and quality pre-owned vehicles. These dealerships also offer maintenance services for vehicles.

Business Development Manager

Part of a new sales process focusing on a centralized sales call center. Developed processes involving outbound marketing campaigns, CRM data accuracy, and KPIs.

THREE DEEP MARKETING | Saint Paul, MN | 2013-2013

Three Deep Marketing is a marketing technology company specializing in customer acquisition, marketing optimization, and measurement of results.

Contact Center Associate

Worked in a team environment-participated as a team leader and individual contributor depending on the project and client needs. Focused on growing market channels for customers through targeted programs. Assessed new and current clients advertising and marketing programs, making recommendations for improvement.

MIKKEL CHAMBERS

MYPILLOW INC | Chanhassen, MN | 2012 - 2013

MyPillow Inc. is a bedding manufacturing company. The company was founded in 2004. MyPillow prides itself on being American based and all products being American made.

Customer Service Supervisor

Managed 20-30 customer service direct reports, ensuring staff performed customer service principles and practices. Addressed customer service related issues with staff and customers. Supported continuous process improvement initiatives. Provided product manufacturing knowledge to staff and worked effectively with the supply chain.

CODING AND PROGRAMMING PROJECTS - https://github.com/TheRealMpchambers

YOU'RE NIGHT OUT

Application focused on designing community oriented events with minimal clicks and website visits. Acted as project manager managing schedules, deadlines, and component design. Responsible for HTML and CSS user design.

RETROPIE

Customized the operating system of a raspberry pi to allow for a virtual emulator focused on SEGA GENESIS and GameBoy Advanced games.

RPGs, GAMES, and TRIVIA

Designed several web applications with a focus on enjoyment. Responsible for front end and logic development. Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript languages with implementation of several framework libraries.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA - Saint Paul, MN

Certificate in Programming and Coding | September 2018 – March 2019

UNIVERSITY OF ST. THOMAS - Minneapolis, MN

Certified Professional Project Manager | Business Analytics 1 & 2 | Supply Chain | September 2015

BETHEL UNIVERSITY - Arden Hills, MN

Master of Arts | Communication Studies | September 2012 – Present

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY - St. Paul, MN

Bachelor of Arts | Communication Studies | September 2009 – May 2012

MEMBERSHIP & VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

UNITED STATES TENNIS ASSOCIATION | 2017 – Present

MEN'S RECREATIONAL SOCCER LEAGUE | 2017 - Present

LAMBDA PI ETA-XI XI HONOR SOCIETY | 2010 - 2012

UNIVERSITY OF NORTHWESTERN | Journalist for Student Newspaper "The Column": 2010-2012

UNIVERSITY OF NORTHWESTERN CAMPUS OUTREACH | Mentor to students | 2010 - 2012